Finding Aid for the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection LSC.0100
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Author Identified
  - Russell, Bertrand, 3rd Earl Russell, 1872-1970. [Some prospects: cheerful and otherwise]. Circa 1928 22 leaves. 25.5 centimeters. Holograph. (Box 12)
    An essay, titled "The Future." Published in "Sceptical Essays," W. W. Norton, New York, circa 1928, Number XVII, pages 238-256. Another copy: 1 reel 35mm negative microfilm.
  - Russell, Bertrand, 3rd Earl Russell, 1872-1970. What I believe. 1925 January 1 3 p.l., 70 leaves. 22.5 centimeters. Holograph. (Box 12)
    First published by Kegan Paul, Trench, Trubner & Co., London, 1925, in its series, "Today and Tomorrow." Another copy: 1 reel 35mm negative microfilm.
  - Russell, David Abel, 1780-1861. To Herman A. Sheldon, Washington D.C. 1840 March 20 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Russell, Representative from New York, sends his autograph.
  - Ruthven, Madeleine. 7 poems., n.d.; (8 items, 38pp. [typescript, photocopy]). (Box 288, Folder 9)
    Includes short introduction Sondelius Came to the Mountains, by Herbert Klein.
    Gift of Jake Zeitlin.
  - Todd Ruthven, 1914-1978. Ten poems. [Edinburgh, T. & A. Constable, Ltd., at the University Press] 1940. 1940 [16] p. 17 cm. (Box 6)
    Edition limited to 150 copies, of which this is Number 44. With this is bound: Holograph manuscript of Ten Poems, plus 2 additional poems, In Edinburgh, June 1940 and During an air-raid. Presentation copy to Peter Watson, Edinburgh, July 24, 1940. Bound in marbled wrappers.
  - Sackville-West, Hon. Victoria Mary (Vita), 1892-1962. Correspondence. V.P., V.D. 1931 May 6 1 item. Typescript, signed. (Box 5)
    1 postcard to Mssrs. Wm. Jackson, Ltd.
  - Sansom, George B. 1 als. 1942 (Box 5)
    Removed from book.
  - Saltonstall, Leverett, 1781-1845. To Abel Parker Upshur, the Secretary of the Navy, Washington. 1843 July 13 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 32)
  - Saunders, Mira C. Correspondence. 1 folder. (Box 15)
  - Schnitzer, Ewald. Correspondence with various persons., 1965-1966. (Box 197, Folder 2)
    re documentary on Emin Pasha.
  - Schurz, Carl, 1829-1906. To Franklin Hough, Washington. 1877 October 27 (Box 16)
    Schurz, then Secretary of the Interior, acknowledges letter of Hough.
  - Semmes, Benedict J. To Hezikiah Niles, Piscatway, Maryland. 1830 June 26 3 p. Holograph signed. (Box 32)
    Concerning Henry Clay and the election of 1830.
  - Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951. Mailied. Score. 1899 August 8 2.25 page holograph score in ink. In folder. (Box 23)
    Purchase Anna Wetter.
    Oversize. Text by Goethe "Zwischen Weizen und Korn." At end of manuscript, holograph signature in pencil: "Arnold Schnberg Jugendwerk."
  - Scofield, Glenni William, 1817-1891. To Sayen Wood, Warren, Pennsylvania. 1869 (Box 16)
    January 19 1 p. Holograph signed.
  - Scott, Sir Walter, Baronet, 1771-1832. Correspondence. 1823, circa 1827 6 items. Holograph. (Box 19)
    1 letter to John Leycester Adolphus, 1823 July 28. 1 letter to William Taylor, April 23, circa 1827. Dictated.
  - Sergeant, John, 1779-1852. Correspondence and documents. 1819-1842 4 pieces. (Box 30)
    Includes resolves by the Board of Directors of the Bank of the United States, of which Sergeant was chairman, responding to investigating committee of the United States House of Representatives, 1834 May 8.
  - Segar, Joseph, 1804-1885. To Vespucian Ellis, Washington. 1838 June 24 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 10)
  - Seldon, John. [Law article]., n.d.; (Holograph). (Box 187, Folder 2)
    Entitled: The original of "Sect. Jurisd. Testam."
  - Severoli, Leopoldo. Travel log. Hungary., April-December 1809. (Box 194, Folder 12)
  - Seward, Frederick William, 1830-1915. Correspondence. 2 letters in 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Shaw, Lemuel, 1781-1861. To Timothy Boutelle, Boston. 1832 June 30 3 p. Holograph signed. (Box 32)
  - Shanewise, Lenore. Letters to Lemore Shanewise., 1924-1957.; (Photocopies). (Box 199, Folder 10)
    Includes telegrams (photocopies).
  - Shaw, Peter (Physician), 1694-1763. Notes of Shaw's chemistry lecture., 1740 15 January.; (1 item, 25pp. [holograph]). (Box 282, Folder 19)
    Notes apparently taken by student.
    Cover title: "Dr. Shaw's Lecture in Chemistry 15 of January 1740."
  - Shee, Sir Martin Archer, 1769-1850. Correspondence. circa 1830 2 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
    1 letter to Daniel Egerton, 1830 March 8. Sidmouth, Henry Addington, 1st viscount, 1757-1844. Correspondence to Allan Cunningham. 1834 January 21 1 item. Holograph.
  - Shock, Samuel. Letter, Harrisburg to Editor of the Presbyterian. 1835 December 5 1 p. 14 centimeters. Printed form and holograph signed. (Box 10)
  - Sibley, M[ark] H[opkins] 1796-1852. Letter, Washington to unknown. 1837 December 13 3 p. 25 centimeters holograph. (Box 10)
    Endorsement: M. H. Sibley, 1837 December 18, regarding Hotly for Clerk of Assembly.
  - Silliman, Benjamin, 1816-1885. Correspondence. 1831 and 1841 2 items. Holograph. (Box 12)
    1 letter to Dr. John Torrey, 1831 April 29. 1 letter to John Apthorp Vaughan, 1841 December 18.
  - Simmel, Ernst. Correspondence, Berlin and others. 1914-1916, 1929-1931 Circa 650 pieces, in folders. (Box 26)
    Gift: Jack Reynold.
    Family letters covering the period of World War I, 1914-1916. The second group of letters, 1929- 1931, Berlin, relates to the financing of a clinic for psychopathic patients. The clinic was under the supervision of Dr. Sigmund Freud, Anna Freud, and Princess Marie Bonaparte. For detailed list of correspondents consult Collections file.
  - Simms, Rupert. 2 als. 1890, 1893 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Simms, Rupert. Bibliotecha Staffordiensis no. 207.
    List of subscribers to Bibliotecha Staffordiensis, Rupert Simms, comp. 1 printed letter regarding Simms.
  - Simms, William Gilmore, 1806-1870. Correspondence. Circa 1845-1846 3 items. Manuscript. (Box 20)
    1 letter from Simms. Undated, incomplete. 1 letter to Simms from Cornelius Mathews. New York, 1846 October 9. 1 letter to Simms from Richard Spadon. Charleston, South Carolina, 1845 May 9.
  - Simon, O. Letter to S.P. Bancroft., 1936. (Box 194, Folder 3)
    re "Something to Think About" (1931).
  - Simon, AndrT Louis, 1877-1970. Correspondence and photograph. In one folder. (Box 25)
    Includes: letters concerning recording disc of Simon's "This vintage year in France [1950?]" together with a photograph of Simon, and 4 examples of his bookplates.
  - Simone, Edgardo. Footprints - sheet music., n.d.; (1 item, 22pp.). (Box 289, Folder 2)
    Chinese poems set to music. Translations by Kenneth Rexroth.
    Gift of Edgardo Simone.
  - Simons, James. To Col. Richard Hambton. 1790 Oct. 9 Holograph signed. (Box 4)
  - Sinclair, William MacDonald, 1850-1917. Correspondence. 1 folder. (Box 15)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1978. Manuscript., n.d.; (1 item, 1p. [typescript]). (Box 288, Folder 7)
    1 leaf, marked as p.15.
    Note in holograph: Sinclair's article on Jack London(?).
  - Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964. Letters, signed, to various persons. V.p., v.d. 1 item. (Box 4)
  - Skinner, J[ohn] S[tuart] 1788-1851. To Ralph Earle, Baltimore. [1835] July 17 (Box 9)
    Letter concerning Andrew Jackson and John Henry Eaton.
  - Smith, John L. and Aletha Smith (Box 194, Folder 10-11)
    - Documents., 1912-1938. (Box 194, Folder 11)
      Various stock & bond certificates, and correspondence re financial dealings.
      Gift of Ed Cray.
    - Documents., 1911-1938. (Box 194, Folder 10)
      Various stock and bond certificates, title insurance papers, etc.
      Gift of Ed Clay.
  - Smedley, Mrs. Mary (Hume). Correspondence, signed to Robert Baldwin. Dulwich. Circa 1835-1837 7 items. (Box 27)
    Mary Smedley was the wife of Edward Smedley, 1788-1836. Robert Baldwin was Edward Smedley's publisher.
  - Smiles, Samuel, 1812-1904. Correspondence. 2 items. (Box 29)
    Heise purchase: cat. 204. 1952 September 5
  - Smollett, Tobias George, 1721-1771. Correspondence. 8 pieces on 12 leaves. Photocopies (negative). In folder. (Box 35)
    Research Grant Funds.
  - Smith, Jonathan, Letters to George Duffield, Boston, and to Jasper Yeates. 1803 April 15 and 1817 March 13 2 letters. Holograph signed. (Box 30)
  - Snick, Morris. Diary., 1861-1862.; (Holograph). (Box 198, Folder 3)
    Extracts from own diary for 1861-1862, copied in 1886 by author.
    Gift of Hazel Newell.
  - Spaulding, John T. Correspondence. Ca. 1913 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Spaulding, John Tricks. Bibiographical account
    1 als 1913 Dec 3. 1 greeting card signed.
  - Southard, Daniel D. Correspondence. 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. Correspondence. 2 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Spinner, Francis Elias, 1802-1890. Correspondence to E. Bartow, Washington, to Leslie Smith, Washington, and one fragment autographed. 1857 January 20 and 1865 June 29 3 pieces. (Box 16)
  - Spinoza, Benedictus de, 1632-1677. 2 letters and articles., 1930-1940.; (5 items, 5pp. [holograph]). (Box 284, Folder 11)
    All re Spinoza. Articles from the Times (London).
    Found in The Chief Works of Benedict de Spinoza (London: 1891).
  - Sprague, William, 1830-1915. Correspondence to John R. Zimlett, Providence, Rhode Island and to A.A. Pest, Washington. 1864 January 2 and 1869 March 17 2 letters. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Sprague, Senator from Rhode Island, 1863-1875, requests of Zimlett a copy of the enabling act, passed by the state legislature in relation to the National Bank and forwards a note to Pest.
  - Sproul, Robert and Ida (Box 188, 191)
    - Correspondence with F.S. Klingberg., 1936 & 1979. (Box 191, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Flora M. Scott. (Box 188, Folder 9)
      Gift of Flora M. Scott.
    - Newspaper articles., n.d. (Box 188, Folder 10)
  - St. Aubin, Cecil. Borrego Springs earthquake., 1968.; (1 reel-to-reel audio tape). (Box 286, Folder 7)
  - Stael-Holstein, Anne Louise Germain (Necker), baronne de, 1766-1817. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Stanton, Elizabeth Cady, 1815-1902. Correspondence. 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Starrett, Vincent. 1 als. 1918 May 28 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Savage, Philip Henry. First poems and fragments.
  - State Board of Landscape Architects, California. Minutes., 1953-1961. (Box 199, Folder 12)
    Reports for: 1953-1954, 1955, 1956, 1957, 1958-1961.
  - Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946 (Box 191, 284)
    - Photographs., n.d. (Box 191, Folder 9)
      Photographs of a family reunion at Billingin, France.
      Gift of Robert Bartlett Haas.
    - Contract to produce Yes is for a Very Young Man., 1949 18 April.; (1 item, 2pp. [original typescript]). (Box 284, Folder 9)
      Signed by Carl Van Vechten for the Stein Estate.
      Purchase: Houle Gallery and Bookshop.
  - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Correspondence with Jake Zeitlin., 1936.; (7 items, 3pp.). (Box 286, Folder 3)
    Telegram from JZ re speaking engagement, and JS's reply [postcard, telegram and holograph letter].
    Card also under Zeitlin, Jake--correspondence w/JS.
    - Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968. Autograph letter. Los Gatos., 1936. (Box 286, Folder 3)
  - Sterling, George. Interview of Herbert Herren (sp?) by Willard Haughland., (1 reel-to-reel tape - Speed varies). (Box 288, Folder 3)
    See note in folder.
  - Stevens, Thaddeus, 1792-1868. Unaddressed, undated note. 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    "Allow Mr. Painter to see the proof of my speech."
  - Stewart, Frank Mann. Correspondence with various persons., 1933-1961. (Box 200, Folder 6)
    Includes invitations, UCLA events, and photographs.
  - Story, William Wetmore, 1819-1895. Correspondence. 1 piece. (Box 29)
  - Stout, Alfred H. Correspondence. 1850 October 12 2 pages. A.L.S. (Box 8)
    To Peter H[ardeman] Burnett, Rio Chico, Butte County, California. Requesting to be appointed to the post of "Collector of Foreign Taxes" for his district.
  - Stoutenburg, Thomas D.W. 1 als. 1850 Dec 18 (Box 5)
    Gift of Mr. Jesse Merritt.
  - Stretton, Hesba, 1832-1911. Letters, signed, to various persons. v.p., v.d. 16 items. Holograph. (Box 6)
    "Hesba Stretton" was the pseudonym of Sarah Smith.
  - Strutt, Joseph, 1749-1802. Correspondence. 1 piece. (Box 29)
  - Stuart, Eldridge Amos. Memoirs of Amos Eldridge Stuart (dictated 1939-1943)., n.d.; (Typescript). (Box 189, Folder 2)
    Gift of J. Weaver.
  - Summers, Montague, 1880-1948. Correspondence, holograph signed, to [Havelock] Ellis. 9 from 43 Broad St., Oxford, 1931 - 1932, 1928. 10 pieces. (Box 7)
    9 letters from 43 Broad St., Oxford, 1931 Aug 13 - 1932 Feb 29. 1 letter from Richmond, Surrey, 1928 Apr 30. Discussing Thomas James Wise's antagonism at not receiving an advance copy of his Dryden research work he did on Charley Wag, attributing authorship to George Augustus Sala; and other bibliographic matters. Including newspaper clipping dated 1932 Jan 12 from the Daily Telegraph of review ofbook; also assails John Hayward who criticized his dryden book in the Times Literary Supplement. Letter Feb. 25, 1932 gives details of some The Dramatic Works of John Dryden.
  - Supervielle, Jules, 1884-1960. [Poem]. undated 5 leaves. 28 centimeters. Holograph. (Box 12)
    Original draft with copious corrections. Publishing history unknown.
  - Swartwout, Samuel, 1804-1867. Correspondence. 1830-1831 10 letters. (Box 32)
    Written as Collector of the Port of New York.
  - Swedenberg, H.T., Jr., 1906-1978. 2 notebooks and book loan and order forms., ca. 1938.; (4 items, approximately 128pp. [holograph]). (Box 282, Folder 20)
    Notebooks titled "Literary Criticism," and "Medieval Romance and Medieval Drama."
  - Symonds, John Addington, 1840-1893. Correspondence. 1891 January 12 1 item. Holograph. (Box 12)
    1 letter to William Barclay Squire.
  - Symons, Arthur, 1865-1945. Correspondence. 3 items. Holograph. (Box 12)
    A photograph of Symons is on the reverse of an undated postcard to an unknown person. 1 letter to Grant Richards, 1920 (?) September 17. 1 letter to Elkin Mathews, undated.
  - Symons, Julian, 1912-1994. Correspondence to Holbrook Jackson. 1939 March 31 1 p. typescript. (Box 20)
    From "20th century verse, February 1929."
  - Takahashi, Margaret O'Brien. Interview., n.d.; (2 audio tapes [reel-to-reel]). (Box 286, Folder 6)
  - Talleyrand-Perigord, Charles Maurice de, prince de Benevent, 1754-1838. Commission, London. 1833 April 25 2 p. Document signed (with seal). (Box 5)
    Gift of Edward Kaufman, November 1949.
    Document appointing Joseph Rabotteau keeper of his lands of Valencay.
  - Tappan, William Bingham, 1794-1849. Correspondence. 1 piece. (Box 29)
  - Tautphoeus, Jemima (Montgomery) Freifrau von, 1807-1893. Correspondence. August 18 1 folder. (Box 7)
    Purchase: Maggs, 1952 December 30.
    Holograph letter signed to "My Dear Henrietta," dated August 18th, discussing a Tirol journey.
  - Taylor, Henry, Sir, 1800-1886. Correspondence and papers. v.p., 1828-1829.; (28 items, manuscript). (Box 172)
    Concerning the publication of The School of Fashion.
  - Taylor, Sir Henry, 1800-1886. Correspondence. 1 piece. (Box 29)
    Heise purchase: cat. 197.
  - Taylor, Isaac. Letters to Messrs Taylor & Hessey, Booksellers, London., 1814-1823. (Box 192, Folder 6)
    8 letters re finances and book publishing.
    Purchased from J. Schiller, 1986.
  - Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, 1st baron, 1809-1892. Correspondence. 1830 June 18 and 1876 October 25 2 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
    1 letter to Effingham Wilson, 1830 June 18. 1 letter to Mrs. [Catherine] Gladstone, 1876 October 25.
  - [Thackerary, William Makepeace] 1811-1863. Little Billee. n.p. (English). undated 4 leaves. Illustrated. 24.5 centimeters. Manuscript. (Box 15)
    First published in "Sand and Canvas: a Narrative of Adventures in Egypt, with a Sojourn among the Artists in Rome," by Samuel Beran, London, Charles Gilpin, 1849. Reprinted as "The Three Sailors," in "Ballads and Songs," by William Makepeace Thackeray, London, Cassell & Co., 1896. This manuscript copy differs in several respects from the printed copies. It is not known in whose hand this manuscript is written. Five pen and ink drawings by an unknown artist illustrating this poem are mounted on the leaves of the manuscript. Bound in brown morocco. With this: a clipping from "The Nation," 1913 November 6, about this manuscript.
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863. Correspondence, signed, to various persons. 17 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    2 letters to Lady Olliffe (wife of Sir Joseph Francis Olliffe, 1808-1869), 1861 November 4 and undated. 1 letter to Henry Alworth Merewether, undated. 1 letter to Sir Joseph Francis Olliffe, undated. 1 letter to Sir Theodore Martin, undated. 1 letter to Lady Helena Saville Martin, undated. 1 letter to John Kenyon, 1868 February 12. 1 letter to Abraham Hayward, 1849 January 3.
  - Thome, Joseph R. Problems which obstruct the process of title distribution under Bolivian agrarian reforms., 1966 September. (Box 188, Folder 2)
    In holograph: "Preliminary report." Including letter (1970) to Professor James Wilkie (UCLA-History).
  - Thompson, James Westfall. Letters, ms., etc. removed from James Westfall Thompson books. (Box 4)
  - Thorne, Marco G. Diary of Levi Stovell, 1849., 1940.; (Bound). (Box 189, Folder 4)
    M.A. (Stanford University).
  - Thompson, Richard Wigginton, 1809-1900. Unaddressed note. 1881 October 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    "Yours very truly and respectfully R.W. Thompson" [Secretary of the Navy, 1877- 1881].
  - Thurston, Mrs. Katherine Cecil, 1875-1911. Correspondence to Messrs. Perrie and Cazenove, literary agency, London. 1902-1910 65 items. Holograph. (Box 12)
    This correspondence concerns the selling and publishing of Mrs. Thurston's literary works.
  - Tilghman, William, 1756-1827. To General Samuel Smith, Baltimore, Maryland. 1826 (Box 16)
    November 26 2 p. Holograph signed.
  - Tomlinson, Henry Major, 1873-1958. Correspondence. 2 letters. (Box 29)
    Gift: Flo and Jo Swerling.
  - Traubel, Horace 1909 or 1904 January 19 1 als. (Box 7)
  - Train, George Francis, 1829-1904. To Edward Edmund Cooper, New York. 1866 June 26 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 32)
    Robert E. Cowan purchase.
    Train, author and railroad promoter, asks for Cooper, Representative from Tennessee, to give his attention to the attempt by Thaddeus Stevens to prevent the alteration of the route of the Union Pacific Railroad, and hopes that President Andrew Johnson will "put his foot down" in the matter as he did in previous matters. 3 clippings attached to the letter.
  - Trelawny, Edward John, 1792-1881. Correspondence. circa 1860 2 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
    1 letter to his daughter, Prue, 1860 July 10.
  - Trowbridge, John W. To Henry O'Reilly, Oswego, New York. 1837 August 14 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning supporters and meetings of Anti-Monopoly Party in Oswego County and New York City.
  - Trumbull, Lyman, 1813-1896. To Elisha Foote, Washington. 1869 April 3 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Letter from Trumbull, Senator from Illinois, to Foote, Commissioner of Patents, introducing a Mrs. Cameron for a writing position.
  - Trumbo, Dalton and Tom Reed. Love Begins at Twenty - screenplay., (1 item, 103pp. [typescript carbon]). (Box 284, Folder 4)
    Donor: Barbara Case (JFK Memorial Library, CSULA).
  - Tully, Richard Walton, 1877-1945. Correspondence. 2 letters in 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Turner, O. To Henry O'Reilly, Southport, New York (?). 1828 July 18 3 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning the meetings and organization of the local supporters of Andrew Jackson, and their Anti-Mason opponents, as reported to O'Reilly, editor of the Jacksonian Rochester, New York Advertiser.
  - Turner, Walter James, 1889-1946. Fossils of a future time? London, Oxford University Press. 1946 108 sheets. Galley proofs with extensive holograph corrections in ink. (Box 28)
    Gift of Claude E. Jones, 1963 February.
    A book of poems.
  - Tyndale-Briscoe, C. E. 1928 1 als (and transcript) 1928 Oct 24 1 tl (signature torn off) (and transcript) (Box 7)
  - U.K. Home Office. Bureau of Social Affairs, Tokyo. Social work in Japan., 1934.; (Typed). (Box 189, Folder 1)
    Excerpts.
  - Upward, Allen, 1863-1926. Draft memo of an agreement with the Today Publishing Co., Ltd. (?). London. 1905 March 7 leaves. Holograph manuscript with a few pencil corrections. (Box 25)
    Purchase: Bertram Rota.
    Allen Upward agrees to write weekly articles for "Today." Number of words specified and rates given.
  - U.S. Armory, Harper's Ferry, Va. Records. 1837-1841 36 items (1 folder). (Box 9)
    Correspondence, reports, notices, orders, et cetera pertaining to the administration of the Armory at Harper's Ferry, chiefly in the handwriting of Edward Lucas, Jr., Superintendent of the Armory. Includes reports from the Master Armorer and the Watchman concerning details of their work.
  - United States Colored Troops (Box 191, Folder 10-11)
    - U.S. Army documents - Civil War period., 1864-1865. (Box 191, Folder 10)
      Muster and muster-out rolls (33d Regiment), pay voucher (110th Regiment), and memorandum (35th Regiment).
    - U.S. Army documents., 1865-1867. (Box 191, Folder 11)
      Muster rolls, pay vouchers, letters and discharge vouchers for 33rd, 35th, 82d and 128th Regiments.
  - University Hospital Medical School & Clinic. Minutes book., 1920-1922. (Box 198, Folder 1)
    For stock holders and trustees meetings.
  - Valdez, Luis (Box 190, 286)
    - Interview by John Weaver., 1978.; (Typescript). (Box 190, Folder 1)
    - Interview[?]., 1978 22 August.; (1 reel-to-reel and cassette). (Box 286, Folder 8)
  - Vallejo, P. (Dr.) correspondence. 1875 March 29 (Box 7)
    Telegram sent by Mrs. J. B. Cooper. San Francisco.
  - Van Dyke, Henry Herbert, 1809-1888. To William S. Martien, Albany, New York. 1838 March 12 (Box 31)
  - Vandenhoff, Anne. Diary., 1941-1945.; (Holograph, bound and typescript). (Box 197, Folder 3)
    re Los Angeles during World War II.
    Gift of Anne Vandenhoff.
  - Vanderhoff, George, American actor. Correspondence. 1 piece. (Box 29)
  - Vanderpoel, Aaron, 1799-1871. Correspondence to F[rancis] P[reston] Blair, Washington and to James K[irke] Paulding, [Washington]. 1839 December 12 and 18 2 letters. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning issues of the Congressional Globe of which Blair was editor. Paulding was Secretary of the Navy at this time.
  - Vibbard, C. Correspondence to Erastus Corning. Schenectady, New York. 1850 July 1 and 8 2 letters. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
  - Vinton, Samuel Finley, 1792-1862. To H[ezekiah] Niles, Washington. 1832 December 16 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning the political crises of that year, the sentiment in Congress toward and adjustment of the Tariff of 1832, toward Andrew Jackson and his stand against the Nullification Proclamation of S.C., and the attitude of party men in Baltimore and Richmond on these subjects.
  - Vlaminck, Maurice de, 1876-1958. Letters and manuscript., 1949-1950.; (9 items, 27pp. [holograph, signed] and [typescript w/corrections, signed]). (Box 288, Folder 11)
    3 letters to S.H. Roth w/envelopes. Manuscript [in French] in 5 sections (pp.35-57 [pp.41-43 & 47 missing]).
    Purchase: Zeitlin and Brugge.
  - Vosper, Robert. Interview., n.d.; (Typescript). (Box 201, Folder 3)
  - Voynich, Ethel Lilian (Boole) 1864-1960. Correspondence. 1930-1933 4 items. (Box 7)
    Removed from: Her, Jack Raymond (1901) and An interrupted friendship (1910).
    Correspondence, signed, to Myrtle A. Crummer (Mrs. LeRoy Crummer). New York. Dr. and Mrs. LeRoy Crummer lived in Los Angeles.
  - Wallace, Henry A. (Box 192, Folder 9-10)
    - Correspondence with Sam & Dorothy Glane., 1946-1947.; (4 letters). (Box 192, Folder 9)
      Also, reprint of Thomas Stokes article re Wallace.
    - Articles., n.d. (Box 192, Folder 10)